人人影视原创翻译
风起时尘土飞扬 重调轴
注：该版本片源有前情提要，原字幕无前情提要部分
翻译 草草 小酸奶
原轴 没有影子   后期 8T  总监 小酸奶
对于你们很多人
For many of you,
这次博洛尼亚任务将是你们的最后任务
this Bologna mission will be your last.
这话我只能直说
There's no other way of telling you that.
这是基本统计数据告诉我们的
Just basic statistics tell us that.
所以
So...
如果你们有谁
if any of you should find yourself
第二十二条军规  第三集
落在了统计数据不好的那边
on the wrong side of the statistics,
虽然这话可能有些多余
and at the risk of stating the obvious,
但我想说  你的牺牲
I would like to point out that your sacrifice
将不会白费
will not have been in vain.
地中海战区
洛伦佐  莱昂纳多
Lorenzo, Leonardo!
好  好
Good, good.
约塞连  见到你真好
Yossarian! Lovely to see you.
迈洛  你好吗
Hi, Milo. How's tricks?
很好  尝尝那汤
Good. Try that soup.
吉阿尼
Gianni.
给约塞连一勺汤
Give Yossarian a spoonful of that zuppa.
尝尝这个吧
Wait till you try this.
天呐  迈洛
My God, Milo.
这难道不是你喝过的最好的西红柿汤吗
Tell me that's not the best tomato soup you've ever had.
真是我喝过的最好的西红柿汤
That's the best tomato soup I ever had.
天呐  那些意大利人真会做饭
Jesus, those Italians can cook,
哪怕是那些小孩
even the little ones.
我今天得去威尔士
I gotta go to Wales today.
我们要从那里进很特别的货
We got something really special coming from there.
你不会相信的
You won't believe it.
司务长
听着
Hey, listen.
我得...
I have to--
我得问你件事
I have to ask you something.
随便说  什么事
Anything. What is it?
如果我叫你把这个
What would you say if I asked you
放那汤里
to put this...
你会怎么说
into that soup?
约塞连  那是洗衣粉
Yossarian, those are laundry flakes.
我不想飞博洛尼亚  迈洛
I don't want to fly Bologna, Milo.
我们很多人都会死的
A whole lot of us are gonna die.
约约  你尝过了  这简直是神菜
Yo-Yo, you tasted this. It's a masterpiece.
是的  而这个完全无味
It is, and these are completely tasteless, man.
-我保证  -你怎么知道
- I promise you. - How do you know that?
相信我  相信我吧
Trust me, I-- just trust me.
这个生意都是建立在我的好名声上的
This enterprise is built on my good name,
我有职责维系我的名声
and it's my job to uphold that name.
博洛尼亚很糟糕  会非常糟糕的
Bologna's bad. It's gonna be really bad.
如果我们病个几天
And if we're sick for a couple days,
第十步兵团就会在地面替我们完成任务了
the 10th Infantry will do the job for us on the ground.
我是司务长  约约  这是神圣的职务
I'm the mess officer, Yo-Yo. It's a sacred office.
我的神圣职务是确保你吃饱
My sacred duty is to keep you fed
营养充足  不是害你重病
and well-nourished, not to make you grievously ill.
拉克斯
你的神圣职责是保住我们的性命
Your sacred duty is to keep us alive.
我宁可生病也不想死
I'd rather be ill than dead.
-各位  -约约
- Fellas. - Hey, Yo-Yo.
今晚的晚饭很重要
Dinner tonight is very important.
-别喝汤  -你说什么呢
- Don't eat the soup. - The hell are you talking about?
别喝汤就是了  好吗
Just don't eat the soup, okay?
好  不喝汤
Okay. No soup.
敬克莱文杰  各位
Here's to Clevinger, guys.
敬克莱文杰
To Clevinger.
克莱文杰
Clevinger.
-克莱文杰  -真可怜
- Clevinger. - Poor kid.
或许他就是一路飞到了瑞士
Maybe he just kept flying, flew off to Switzerland.
不  克莱文杰不会那么做的  不会不告诉我们
No, Clevinger wouldn't do that, not without telling us.
或许他会寄明信片来
Well, maybe we'll get a postcard.
你想跟我一起去瑞士吗  约约
You want to come to Switzerland with me, Yo-Yo?
去见见克莱文杰
Visit Clevinger?
我不想拿克莱文杰开玩笑
I don't want to joke about Clevinger.
好吧
Okay.
但你想跟我一起去瑞士吗
But want to come to Switzerland with me?
相信我  我考虑过的
Believe me, I thought about this.
开小差不是解决办法
AWOL isn't the answer,
除非你想余生都做逃犯
not unless you want to spend the rest of your life as a fugitive.
但这反正也只是空谈
But it's all academic anyway
因为  你的油是不够飞到可行的地方的
'cause you never have enough gas to get anywhere useful.
假如你的油足够呢
Well, but let's say you did have enough gas.
你会去哪
Where would you go?
那也不会去瑞士
Well, it wouldn't be Switzerland.
瑞士人有法律责任把你关起来
The Swiss are legally obliged to lock you up.
他们几乎跟德国人一样
They're practically Germans.
如果你的油足够  其实不够的
If you had enough gas, which you don't,
最好的选择是飞过瑞士
your best bet would be to fly straight over Switzerland,
去瑞典
head to Sweden.
那是你的研究结果吗
That's what your research told you?
瑞典比瑞士强
Sweden's better than Switzerland.
为什么
Oh, why's that?
在瑞典
Well, in Sweden,
你可以跟声音甜如蜜的美女
you can swim nude with beautiful girls
一起裸泳
with voices like honey.
你还可以生一群
And, uh, you can sire whole happy tribes
约塞连的私生子
of illegitimate Yossarians
想跟几个瑞典女人生都行
with any number of Swedish women
你不需要娶她们
who you don't have to marry,
你们大家都可以住在一个屋檐下
and you can all live in the same house,
大家都处得好
and we all get along,
国家会提供免费生育  教育
and the state supplies free child birth, free education,
还让那些小约塞连
and launches all the little Yossarians
都能不被歧视地长大
into a life without stigma.
大家都开心  我的妻子都爱我
Everybody's happy, and all my wives love me.
她们真的裸泳吗
Do they really swim nude?
一丝不挂  基德·桑普森
Totally nude, Kid Sampson.
一丝不挂
Totally nude.
今晚能做好梦了
Sweet dreams tonight.
天呐
Oh, boy.
约塞连
Yossarian?
-都知道什么了  -什么知道什么
- What do we know? - About what?
就是那本你要读的大厚书
About the big book you were gonna read?
什么大厚书
What big book?
关于我怎样才能回家的大厚书
The big book on how I get to go home.
-那本啊  -是啊
- Oh, that one. - Yeah, that one.
东西不多  而且我现在不能说
Not much, and-- and I can't talk right now.
为什么不能
Why not?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你的脑袋在干什么
What are you doing with your head?
我不能当着卡斯卡特的面说
I can't talk in front of Cathcart.
他没在听
He's not listening.
我有进展  但我现在不能说
I'm making progress, but I can't talk right now.
什么进展
What progress?
-我现在不能说  -天呐
- I can't talk about it now. - Christ.
什么进展
What progress?
最后边疆
天呐
Holy Christ!
你们怎么样了
How you boys bearing up?
不是很好  医生
Oh, not so great, Doc.
明天是肯定不能
Hey, uh, there's no way in hell
飞去博洛尼亚了吧
that Bologna's happening tomorrow, right?
博洛尼亚取消了
Oh, Bologna's off.
"别喝汤"
"Don't eat the soup"!
你知道他们明天还会
You know they'll just be sending us
再派我们过去的
straight back up there tomorrow.
你总有一天会谢我的  麦克沃特
You'll thank me one day, McWatt.
你觉得这能持续多久
How long you think the squirts last?
至多几天吧
Couple days at most?
我们最迟后天还是要上天
We'll be right back up there day after tomorrow, latest.
不会的
No, we won't.
第10步兵团正在前往博洛尼亚
10th Infantry is headed to Bologna right now.
他们会替我们打掉高射炮
They'll clean out those artillery guns for us.
天呐  你是真不理解这里面的门道啊
Oh, man, you really don't know how this works.
我看到图表了  第10步兵团只有两天就到
I saw the charts. 10th is less than two days out.
你真是不理解这里的门道啊
You really don't know how this works.
我不知道什么的门道
I don't know how what works?
一切  约塞连
Everything, Yossarian.
-这就是重点  -什么重点
- That's the point. - What point?
-你想说什么  -没错
- What's your point? - Exactly.
这都是数字游戏
It's all a numbers game,
等你的命数到了  那就是到了
and when your number's up, your number's up.
去你的数字  麦克沃特
Screw your numbers, McWatt.
约塞连
Hey, Yossarian!
上来
Jump in.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
我在威尔士找来的
I picked it up in Wales.
找到了满满一仓库呢
I found a warehouse full.
65辆在路上  35辆在水上
65 on land, 35 on water.
等战争结束  我就把它们运去明尼苏达州
When the war is done, I ship 'em to Minnesota.
我有事问你
Hey, I got a bone to pick with you.
他们还是要派你们去博洛尼亚
They're still gonna send you to Bologna.
所以昨天有什么意义
So what was the point of yesterday?
等士兵们不再拉肚子了
As soon as the men can hold their guts in,
你们就还得再去博洛尼亚
you're gonna go back to Bologna.
是啊  但这次我们就有地面支持了
Yeah, but this time, we got ground support.
我有坏消息告诉你  朋友
I got bad news for you, my friend.
你的地面支持改道了
Your ground support has been rerouted
不去博洛尼亚  而是去阿詹蒂
from the Bologna road to the Argenti road,
就是因为皮亚诺萨空军基地大面积爆发疾病
due to a mass illness on the Pianosa Air Base,
但没事的  伙计
but it's gonna be all right, pal.
梅杰·梅杰少校
我得见少校
I need to see the Major.
你现在不能见他  长官
You can't see him right now, sir.
那我什么时候能见他
Well, when can I see him?
等他去吃午餐时
When he goes out to lunch.
那时你就能进去了
Then you can go right in.
抱歉  你再说一遍
I'm sorry, say that again?
梅杰少校在办公室时
Major Major never sees anyone in his office
是不在他办公室见人的
while he's in his office.
那你说我什么时候能见他
So when are you saying I can see him?
基本上见不到  长官
Pretty much never, sir.
-梅杰  -我得请你离开  长官
- Hey, Major! - I'm gonna have to ask you to leave, sir!
-梅杰  -拜托  长官
- Major! - Come-- Sir!
约塞连
Yossarian.
你的手下真是疯了
Your man has lost his mind.
他吗  他就是...
Oh, him? He's--he's just--
天呐
Oh, God. Jesus.
你到底有什么进展
So what's this progress you say you've made?
-什么进展  -进展
- What progress? - The progress.
你在翻看行动手册
You were going through the operations manual,
你那晚告诉我你有进展
and you told me the other night that you made progress.
我没有任何进展
I haven't made any progress.
-你读了吗  -很不好读的
- Did you read it? - It's very difficult to read.
我们不能飞博洛尼亚
We can't fly Bologna.
这十天里  其他中队已经掉了
36 planes from other squadrons have already gone down
36架飞机
in the last ten days.
那里简直是B-25坟场
It's a B-25 boneyard down there.
你如果不害怕就不正常了
Well, you wouldn't be normal if you weren't afraid.
就连最勇敢的人也会害怕
Even the bravest men experience fear.
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
你为什么参军
Why did you join up?
因为这是正确的做法  做好事
Because it was the right thing--to do good.
没错  你在这里就能做好事
Exactly, and you can do good from right here.
你在这里就能拯救生命
You can save lives from right here.
我不懂
I-I don't understand
你究竟以为我能做什么
exactly what it is that you think I can do.
你是个少校  你是梅杰·梅杰·梅杰少校
You're a Major. You're Major Major Major Major.
-你可以签署东西  -签署什么
- You can just sign things. - Sign what?
-表格  -什么表格
- The form. - What form?
让我们停飞的表格
The form to stand us down.
为什么要你们停飞
To stand you down, why?
让我们停飞
To stand us down, you know,
因为对生命和肢体有不合理威胁
for unreasonable risk to life and limb.
我没有停飞一个中队的权利
I don't have the power to stand down a squadron
连一个机组都不行
or even a crew.
那就我一人  让我停飞
Then just me. Stand me down.
那要是人人都这么想呢
Oh, s-suppose everybody felt that way.
那我要是不这么想不是太傻了
Then I'd certainly be a damn fool to feel any other way,
是不是
wouldn't I?
那么  你要我让你停飞
So you want me to stand you down
而你的朋友去飞博洛尼亚
while your friends fly Bologna?
为什么不行
Why not?
这个决定并不会比
It wouldn't be any more or less arbitrary
任何其他替我做出的决定更武断
than any other decision that gets made on my behalf.
我不怕德国人
I'm not afraid of the Germans.
我怕卡斯卡特认为
I am afraid of Cathcart deciding
我还得飞更多任务
that I need to fly more missions.
我怕那个决定地图上
I'm afraid of the person who decides
轰炸线该画在哪的人
where the bomb line goes on the map.
那人是谁
Who is that person?
我们现在就是这样
And that's what it's come down to for us.
我们怕地图上的线
We're afraid of a line on a map.
你知道那是什么感觉吗
Do you know what that feels like?
害怕一条线
To be afraid of a piece of string?
博洛尼亚
抱歉打扰你  长官
Sorry to disturb you, sir.
我们拿下博洛尼亚了  长官
We've captured Bologna, sir.
谁拿下博洛尼亚了
What-- Who's captured Bologna?
我不知道  长官
I don't know, sir.
我去了简报室  长官
I was in the briefing room, sir.
轰炸线现在在博洛尼亚以北60英里了
The bomb line is now 60 miles north of Bologna.
谢谢  列兵
Thank you, Private.
长官
Sir.
长官  是我  科恩
Sir, it's me, sir--Korn.
-怎么了  科恩  -抱歉叫醒你
- What is it, Korn? - I'm sorry to wake you.
但您应该想知道
But I thought you'd like to know.
我们拿下博洛尼亚了
We captured Bologna.
-什么时候  -夜里时  长官
- When? - Overnight, sir.
轰炸线现在在城市以北60英里处了
The bomb line is now 60 miles north of the city.
-简直太棒了  -我也觉得
- That's goddamn terrific. - I thought so too.
我要去取消任务吗
Yeah, so should I go ahead and cancel the mission?
你当然应该取消任务
Of course you should cancel the mission.
我们总不能轰炸自己人
We're not gonna bomb our own men, are we?
当然  当然不能  长官
Of course-- of course not, sir.
当然不能
Of course not.
约约
Yo-Yo!
约约  醒醒
Yo-Yo, wake up now!
你想听点消息吗
Hey, you want to hear some news?
-第10步兵团拿下了博洛尼亚  -什么
- The 10th Infantry took Bologna. - What?
他们晚上时拿下了那里
They fucking took it overnight.
我去  我去
Holy shit. Holy shit.
我可以见我的姑娘了  我可以去罗马了
I get to see my girl! I'm going to Rome!
你们谁是迈洛·迈德邦德
Which one of you is Milo Minderbinder?
你好  少校  是我
Oh, hello, Major. That'd be me.
羊排先生
Oh, Mr. Lamb Chops.
没错  长官
That's right, sir.
小子  为什么他们告诉我所有
Well, now, why is it, son, that they tell me that all
非战斗飞机都得向你征用
non-combat planes have to be requisitioned through you?
指挥链  长官
Chain of command, sir.
伊曼纽尔  快点
Emanuele, rapido, rapido.
-我需要架飞机去博洛尼亚  -博洛尼亚
- I need a plane to Bologna. - Bologna?
我们已拿下了博洛尼亚  我得去博洛尼亚
We have taken Bologna. I need to go to Bologna.
我们拿下了博洛尼亚
We've taken Bologna?
是的  孩子  我们拿下了博洛尼亚
Yes, son. We have taken Bologna.
罗马
我不懂
I don't understand.
你为什么不干脆付三个的钱
Why don't you just pay for all three
让另两个走
and send the other two away?
因为  那样柯拉拉会气我
Because then Clara will be angry with me
让她工作
for making her work
而给其他人钱让她们放假
and paying the others to have the night off.
她说如果我真心喜欢她
She says that if I really liked her,
我就让她休息一晚
then I'd give her the night off
跟其他几个中的一个上床
and go to bed with one of the others.
他们每人30美元
And they're $30 each?
是的  30美元
Yeah, it's, uh, $30.
30美元买这样的女人可太贵了
$30 is a lot of money for pieces like these.
再说  我这辈子从来不用花钱
Besides, I've never paid for it in my life.
不  你不懂
No, you don't understand--
你不用付钱
you don't have to pay for a thing.
我会付三个人的钱  你们只需要带走另外俩
I'll pay for all three-- you guys just need to take the other two
这样她就不会生气了
so she doesn't get her nose out of joint.
我就是无法理解
I just don't understand why you--
你到底为什么要付钱给她的朋友
why you have to pay for her friends in the first place.
为了哄她开心
To make her happy!
我记得有次
You know, I remember this one time
我骗了俩傻帽高中女生
we tricked these two dumb high-school girls
进了一个兄弟会
into the fraternity.
然后威胁要告诉她们父母
Made them put out for all the fellas
她们跟所有男生发生了关系
by threatening to call their folks
逼她们跟所有男生发生关系
and tell them they were putting out for the fellas.
那是什么意思"发生关系"
And what is it, "putting out"?
就是上  干
Screw, fuck, you know.
所以你骗了那俩姑娘
Ah, so you-- you tricked the girls,
然后还干了她们
and you fuck them?
是啊  就是开开心
Yeah, sure. It was a bit of fun.
那俩姑娘呢  她们也开心吗
And the girls? They were having fun?
当然了
Yes, of course.
那你逼她们开心了  是吗
So you made them have fun, yes?
是吗
Yes?
你们听到了吗
You get a load of this shit?
我被一个做卖女人生意的家伙训了
I'm getting lectured by a guy who sells women for a living.
我清楚自己的职业
I'm aware of my profession.
内特利
Nate-er-ly?
有问题吗
Is problem?
我就来  就来
I-I'm coming. I'm coming.
约约  你可以带走另两个吗
Yo-Yo, come on, will you take the other two?
帮帮忙吧
Help me out here, man.
博洛尼亚
好伙计
My good man.
你可以告诉我
Would you be kind enough to provide me
这栋建筑的合法拥有者的名字吗
with the name of the legal owner of this building?
我要征用它
I wish to requisition it
给美国战士使用
for the fighting men of the United States of America.
什么
Scusi?
就是
The...
是啊  我尽量
Yeah, I am. I try to be.
那人叫约约
你怎么认识他
他就是从我这儿买了放大镜的人
五美元呢
他是个白痴
这是我妹妹
妹妹
Sister.
她是你妹妹
She's your sister?
对
妹妹  妹妹
Sister, sister.
你吃饭了吗
看着我
你找到虫子了吗
虫子
昆虫
Insects.
昆虫  虫子
Ah, insetti. Insects.
你可以给我买冰淇淋吗
冰淇淋  这个我知道
Gelato-- I know this word.
-冰淇淋  -你想要吗
- Gelato. - You want one?
好吧  她想吃
Okay, she's up for it.
那叫什么
What's that called?
冰淇淋筒
冰淇淋
Ice cream.
比"冰淇淋"说起来顺口多了  不是吗
Rolls off the tongue better than "ice cream," doesn't it?
窗户
窗户  是窗户的意思  是吗
Finestra, that's window, yeah?
窗户
Finestra.
带个R吗
With an R, right?
窗户
你能说英语吗  试试
Can you say "window"? Try that?
-窗户  -窗户  对
- Window. - Window, yeah.
没错
Exactly.
豪车
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
什么
Wha--
该死
Fuck.
她会回来的  伙计
She'll be back, buddy.
该死
God damn it.
德·科瓦里少校失踪了
Major de Coverley has gone missing,
你们中一个混蛋要为此坐牢
and one of you fuckers is going to prison for it.
我知道你就在这里
I know you're here,
我要像捕猎豺狼一样抓到你
and I am going to hunt you down like a jackal,
然后把你钉在我的墙上
and I'm gonna mount you on my fucking wall!
所以  如果有谁知道
So, if any of you knows anything
我的轰炸线是怎么被动的
about my bomb line being moved,
现在就该说出来了
now would be the time to speak up!
因为我肯定要查清此事
Because I am gonna get to the bottom of this.
你们相信我  先生们
You can mark my fucking words, gentlemen.
这是中队的耻辱
This is a black eye on the squadron.
一个好人失踪了  可能是被俘了
A good man has gone missing, presumed captured.
或许是失踪  可能死了
Maybe missing, presumed dead!
而罪魁祸首就在这个房间里
The person who did it is in this room...
现在就在  我都能感觉到
Right now-- I can fucking feel it.
对了
Oh, and by the way,
我们要再回博洛尼亚去
we're going back to Bologna.
相信我
Mark my fucking words.
你们要回去
And you're going back there,
你们要炸飞那些燃料罐
and you are gonna bomb the fuck out of those fuel dumps,
你们要炸飞
and you are going to bomb the fuck out of
那些高射炮
those antiaircraft guns,
我希望战情很险恶
and I hope it's fucking bad.
你们最好祈祷你们不会炸到
And you'd better hope that you don't bomb
他们关押德·科瓦里少校的地方
wherever it is they're holding Major de Coverley.
我还有好消息
And I've got some good news.
我要把任务数从40次提升至45次
I'm raising the mission count from 40 to 45.
我知道你肯定乐意
Oh, I knew you'd like that.
作为对这种叛国行为的惩罚
And as punishment for this act of fucking treason,
我还要把任务次数从45提升至50次
I'm also raising it from 45 to 50.
是有不满吗
Oh, do I sense discontent, hmm?
听着  各位
Well, look, fellas...
我不是不讲理的人
I'm not an unreasonable man.
我们做个交易吧
What's say we make a deal, hmm?
如果那个动了
If the repugnant swamp scum
我轰炸线是死人渣  能站出来
that moved my bomb line were to step forward
承认罪过
and admit his guilt,
我就愿意降低任务数
I would be willing to lower the mission count
从50降至45
from 50 to 45.
即刻生效
Effective immediately.
你个死懦夫
You fucking coward.
解散
Dis-fucking-missed!
博洛尼亚
好了  还有45秒
All right, that's 45 seconds to run.
45秒
45 seconds.
情况不妙  各位
It's getting hot up here, fellas.
下面  就在桥那边
Down there! Just beyond the bridge!
路上有一整支车队
There's a whole convoy on that road!
是啊  我们马上就到
Yeah, we're coming up on it now.
你们上面还好吗
You all right up there?
有我们呢  你没事
We got you, we got you. You're okay.
我们要被打死了  快点
We're getting hammered! Let's go!
好  麦克沃特  航向043
All right, McWatt. Bring her to 043.
保持在4500英尺
Holding steady at 4,500.
043  4500英尺
043 at 4,500.
下面那个是吗
Is that it down there?
下面哪个是吗
Is that what down there?
该死的博洛尼亚
Fucking Bologna.
不不  离博洛尼亚还有13英里呢
No, no, no. It's still 13 miles to Bologna.
该死
Holy shit.
他们用青酱做
They make it with a pesto sauce.
还有帕尔玛干酪
And the parmesan, oh...
真是不一般  我告诉你  科恩
It is something, let me tell you, Korn.
不一般
It is something.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
那是什么啊
What in God's green earth is that?
那是什么
What is that?
是我  是我
It's only me. It's only me.
快  快
梯子
手举起来
Hands in the air!
不  没事  这都是我们的了
No, it's okay! These are ours now!
-我说  "手举起来"  -我听懂了
- I said, "Hands in the air." - Yes, I understand that.
我们有误会
There's been a crossed wire somewhere.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是迈洛
I'm Milo! I'm--
我是司务长  你认识我  上尉
I'm the mess officer. You know me, Captain.
我给你做饭的
I feed you.
说出你有什么事
State your business here.
事  我的事就是生意
Business! My business is business.
这不是军用飞机了  是商用的
These are no longer military, these are trade.
这都是敌机
These are enemy planes.
严格讲
Well, technically speaking,
从今天起  它们不再是了
that's no longer the case as of today.
这个详细地解释了
This explains, in great detail,
这些飞机现在属于财团了
that these are syndicate planes now.
-什么财团  -我们财团
- What syndicate? - Our syndicate.
我们都是财团的一部分  包括你
We're all part of the syndicate, even you.
一切都有理有据
And these are all in order.
我说了  手举起来
I said put your hands in the air!
好的  反正  德国人也是财团
Of course. Anyway, the Germans are part of the syndicate, too,
所以  今天的情况就是
and so what's happening today is,
德国人向财团贡献了三架货机
the Germans are contributing three cargo planes to the syndicate.
这些人是谁
Who are these men?
他们是德国人吗
Are they Germans?
是也不是  他们是代表团
Well, yes and no. They're delegates.
他们今天是代表M&M集团的利益而来
They're here today representing the interests of M&M Enterprises.
我知道你要说什么
No, I know what you're gonna say.
是啊  我们在跟德国人打仗
Sure, we're at war with the Germans,
但德国人也是财团里地位尊贵的成员
but the Germans are also members in good standing of the syndicate,
M&M集团
而且他们付账可比好多
and they pay their bills a lot more promptly
同盟国痛快多了
than a lot of allies of ours I could name.
所以我有职责保护他们作为股东的利益
So it's my job to protect their rights as shareholders,
就像我也会保护你们作为财团成员的利益
just as I will protect yours as members of the syndicate.
放下武器  把武器都放下
Weapons down! Put your goddamn weapons down!
长官  这都是德国飞机和德国飞行员
Sir, these are German flyers, and those are German planes.
你做得对  上尉
And you did the right thing, Captain.
迈洛  文件拿来了吗
Milo, have you got those papers?
是  长官  我可以放下手臂吗  长官
Yes, sir. Can I lower my arms, sir?
放下吧
Lower your arms.
原件和复印件都拿来了吗
Have you got the originals and carbon copies?
-是  长官  都在这里  -科恩
- Yes, sir, they're all right here. - Korn!
迈洛  很抱歉我没把这件事
Milo, I apologize for not passing the relevant information
按指挥链传下去  才造成这场闹剧
down the chain of command-- hence, all this kerfuffle.
从现在起  这些飞机
As of now, these planes
属于M&M集团飞行队了
are part of the M&M Enterprise fleet.
太棒了  跟我来  长官
Beautiful. Follow me, sir.
这些飞机简直太棒了  飞得很好
These planes are a beauty. They fly like a dream.
小心头
Watch your head.
干得好  卢卡
Hey, that's beautiful work, Luca.
完美  谢谢
Perfetto, grazie!
很好  迈洛
Very nice, Milo.
-太棒了  -谢谢  长官
- Very elegant. - Thank you, sir.
我也觉得  长官
I think so, too, sir.
扬基歌
043  4500英尺
043 at 4,500! 043 at 4,500!
-收到吗  约塞连  -听到了吗
- Are you reading me, Yossarian? - Hey, can you hear me?
增加输出
这可不是胡闹的时候
This ain't the time to fuck around, man.
是啊  他们火力好猛
Yeah, they're really lighting it up.
拜托  靠近了吗
Come on, you getting close?
约约  怎么回事
Yo-Yo, what's going on?
飞机有问题
There's something wrong with the plane!
问题...
with the--
飞机有问题吗
Something's wrong with the plane?
什么问题
What's the matter?
就是有问题...
There's just something the matter with--
我不知道
I don't know!
是谁在叫
Who is that screaming?
我是机头里的约塞连
This is Yossarian in the nose!
机头里的约塞连
Yossarian in the nose!
你不是说有什么问题...
Didn't you say there was something the matter--
不是你说有问题吗
I thought you said something was the matter.
这里一切都好  一切都没问题
Everything seems fine up here. Everything's all right.
我听不到
I can't hear you.
我说一切都好
I said everything seems all right.
保持住  4500英尺
Holding steady, 4,500 feet.
快投弹  约约  我们走
Drop those fuckers, Yo-Yo! Let's go!
快点  各位  我们...
Come on, boys, let's--
我说我还是听不到
I said I still can't hear you!
有人在吗
Is anybody there?
我们多接近了
How close are we?
我们投不投弹
Are we dropping or what?
-我听不到  -什么
- Hey, I can't hear you. - What?
我听不到
I can't hear you.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're saying.
-我听不到  -我说我听不到
- I can't hear you! - I said I can't hear you!
我已经吼得够响了
I'm shouting as loud as I can!
通讯器有问题
Look, there's something wrong with the intercom!
-我们得调头  -就因为通讯器吗
- We have to turn back. - For an intercom?
我们不能为了通讯器坏掉而调头
We're not turning back for a broken intercom.
调头  要不我打爆你的脑袋
Turn back, or I'll break your fucking head!
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding, right?
如果我听不到你
I can't do my job
我就不能做我的工作
if I can't fucking hear you up there!
-你可以  -我做不到
Yes, you can! No, I can't!
我觉得我们该走  麦克沃特
I think we need to pull out, McWatt.
绝对不行
No fucking way!
好吧  去你的
Fine. Fuck you.
天呐
Jesus.
所有飞机  这里是"扬基歌"
All planes, this is "Yankee Doodle."
我们要走了
We are pulling out.
我们这里出现了技术故障
We have a technical difficulty here!
好
Good.
知道你的问题是什么吗
Hey, you know what your problem is?
你还觉得你能离开这里
You still think you're gonna get out of here.
-你飞得像你走不了了  -没错
- And you fly like you don't. - Exactly.
我想怎么飞就怎么飞
I fly however the fuck I want.
好啊  想怎么飞就怎么飞吧
Sure, fly however the fuck you want.
但我也在飞机上时别那么干
Just not when I'm in the same plane.
我怎么飞根本毫无区别
Oh, it doesn't make a goddamn bit of difference how I fly.
你就是个懦夫
You're just a coward.
我是你认识的最勇敢的人
I'm the bravest fucking man you know.
好啊  做你该做的吧
Okay, do what you got to do.
我不会告诉别人是你扯断了电线
I mean, I'm not going to tell anyone you pulled those wires.
我不介意
I mean, I-I'm swell with it.
你害怕是可以的
I mean, it's okay if you're afraid.
我不害怕  我只是想保住我们的命
I'm not afraid. I'm just keeping us alive.
是的  你是怕了
Oh, yeah, you are. You're afraid.
天呐  你真荒唐
Oh, Christ, you're ridiculous.
知道你和我之间的区别吗
You know the difference between me and you?
我  开心  开心  开心  然后死
Me, happy, happy, happy, happy, dead.
你呢  担心  担心  担心  然后死
You, worry, worry, worry, worry, dead.
别把我卷进你的破事里  好吗
Don't drag me into your shit, okay?
今天的事抱歉了
Sorry about today.
你刚以为自己快要回家了
Just when you think you're close to heading home,
又加了10次任务  我难以想象那是什么感觉
ten more missions--I-I can only imagine how that must feel.
他真是个禽兽
He's a goddamn monster.
为一个人的罪过惩罚整个中队
To punish the squadron for one man's transgression?
我是不相信
I-I'm not a believer
那种旧约式的惩戒
in that sort of Old Testament retribution myself.
那真是罪过吗
And was it really a transgression?
有意让你的战友为你犯下的罪
Well, to knowingly allow your fellow men to be punished
而受到惩罚
for a crime you committed,
我觉得那算是罪过
I-I would say that's a transgression.
但如果这项罪并非罪呢
But what if the crime wasn't really a crime?
就算是罪  那又如何
Or even if it was a crime, so what?
这惩罚是不理智的
The punishment is irrational.
就这样不理智的惩罚而言
Should that man be held responsible
真该对那人追责吗
for the irrationality of the punishment?
我以为你是最该
I would have thought that you of all people
对此人的行为感到愤慨的
would be incensed at the actions of this person.
他导致你还要再多飞10次任务
He's just caused you to fly ten more missions.
我是很愤慨
I am. I'm incensed.
跟别提可怜的老德·科瓦里少校了
Not to mention poor old Major de Coverly.
那是恶作剧吗  还是破坏行为
Was it a prank? An act of sabotage?
如果是个意外呢
What if it was an accident?
我无法想象那怎么可能是意外
Well, I-I don't see how it could be an accident.
就我的理解  轰炸线是一条绳子
My understanding is the bomb line is a piece of string.
它不会自己动的
It doesn't just move on its own.
那可未必
We don't know that,
卡斯卡特更不能确定
and Cathcart certainly doesn't.
我们怎么知道不是卡斯卡特自己动的
How do--how do we know Cathcart didn't do it himself
就为了提高任务数目  因为他疯了
just to raise the missions, because he's nuts.
他就是个彻头彻尾的疯子
He's crazy as a bedbug.
查普林  疯狂是传染的
Chaplain, insanity is contagious.
除了我们  大家都疯了
Everybody's crazy except for us.
你和我  可得小心
You and I have to be careful.
我们可能是全世界唯一正常的人了
We may be the only sane people in the entire world,
我们整天都在被疯子
and we're bullied and insulted and harassed
欺负  侮辱  骚扰  推搡
and shoved around all day long by insane people.
我们尽职尽责  一次次任务
And we do our duty, mission after mission--
35次  40次  然后还被告知这不够
35, 40--then we're told it's not good enough.
我们如果反对  卡斯卡特那样的人就说
And when we object, people like Cathcart tell us
真正的爱国者都会自豪地去飞他们逼我们飞的
any true patriot would be proud to fly as many missions
不管多少次任务
as they're forcing us to fly.
你这么看的话
You look at it that way,
我不能确定  这个轰炸线家伙
I don't know if this bomb line guy
是不是真做错了
really did the wrong thing.
你明白吗
I mean... You know what I mean?
稍息
At ease, at ease.
坐下  坐下吧
Sit. Sit, please, sit.
你们今天战功不小  各位
You did a lot of damage today, boys.
好样的  我们让他们知道厉害了
Bravo, we gave them the real what-for.
我们损失了12人
We lost 12 men...
12个好人
12 damn fine men.
上帝保佑他们
God rest their souls.
但我们战功赫赫
But we did a lot of damage.
航拍照片已洗出
Aerial photographs are developed.
轰炸轨迹一丝不苟
Bombing patterns are meticulous.
好样的
So job well done.
为了表示感谢
Now, by way of saying thank you...
让你们知道你们的勇敢之举
of letting you know that your brave efforts
是得到了感激的
do not go unappreciated...
我已叫司务长迈洛
I have asked Milo, our fine mess officer,
为你们准备了特别的东西
to come up with something special for you all.
我的个人最爱  烤冰淇淋蛋糕
A personal favorite of mine-- Baked Alaska.
战前我都好久没吃了
Haven't had it since before the war.
来吧  端上来
Come on, boys, bring it in!
这就对了
There you go!
很好  各位
There you go, boys.
迈洛  真不错
Milo, looks great.
真好吃  真好吃
Goddamn yummy! It's goddamn yummy!
是不是  先生们  科恩上校  你说呢
Is it not, gentleman? Colonel Korn, what say you?
是  长官  真好吃
Yes, sir, it's yummy.
迈洛  好样的
Milo, fine job.
你们没拿到吗
Did you not get any?
我说  你们没拿到吗
I say, did you not get any?
我们没分到  长官
We did not, sir.
-我听不到  -我们没分到  长官
- I can't hear you. - We did not, sir.
-你们不想要吗  -不了  谢谢  长官
- Do you not want some? - No, thank you, sir.
今天有一架飞机调头了
One plane turned back today.
那架飞机的机组可以站起来吗
Would the crew of that plane stand up?
这架无畏的飞机的飞行员是谁
And who might the pilot of this intrepid ship be?
-是我  长官  -那是麦克沃特  长官
- That'd be me, sir. - That's McWatt, sir.
麦克沃特
McWatt.
请告诉我  麦克沃特
And pray tell, McWatt,
是什么导致了你们急着赶回基地
what precipitated this urgent need to be back at base?
-通讯器坏了  -大声点  让大家听到
- Broken intercom-- - Speak up so everybody can hear you.
通讯器坏了  长官
A broken intercom, sir.
梅杰少校
Major Major,
你一直在读手册吧
you've been reading the manual, I believe.
跟我们说说  根据你的研习
Tell us, in the course of your studies,
你是否读到有哪一段  哪一条
have you come across a paragraph or a subclause
说明通讯器损坏
that tells you that a broken intercom
可以作为放弃任务的有效
is a valid Procedural Termination Mechanism
规程中止机制
for Mission Abortion?
我不...
I don't, um--
-我还没...  -你是没有
- I haven't necessarily-- - No, you haven't!
因为就没有
Because there isn't one!
我要所有人都好好看看这桌
And I want everyone to take a good look at this table,
因为在这桌上
because at this table,
能看到懦夫的脸
you will see the face of cowardice!
那不是有权吃烤冰淇淋蛋糕的脸
And that is not a face that gets Baked Alaska put in it.
是该死的麦克沃特
It's goddamn McWatt!
-天呐  -快走开  麦克沃特
- Oh, Jesus Christ. - Get out of here, McWatt!
搞什么
What the fuck?
你个混蛋
You piece of shit!
麦克沃特  你个疯子
McWatt, you fucking maniac!
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
来啊  麦克沃特  看看你的本事
Come on, McWatt, let's see what you got.
麦克沃特  你疯了  他在干什么
McWatt, you nut! What's he doing?
-搞他  桑普森  -是啊  基德  搞他
- Yeah, get him, Sampson. - Yeah, Kid, get him!
-加油  基德  搞他  -他来了
- Come on, Kid, get him. - Here he comes.
-来啊  麦克沃特  -他来了
- Come on, McWatt! - Here he comes!
来啊  看看你的本事
Come on! Let's see what you got!
我看到你了  混蛋  来啊  麦克沃特
Oh, I see you, motherfucker. Come on, McWatt.
没错  给他点颜色看看
That's right, give it to him.
基德·桑普森  捅进他屁股里
Kid Sampson, shove it up his ass!
-捅进他屁股里  -来啊
- Shove it right up his ass! - Come on!
捅进他屁股里
Shove it up his ass!
我要插进你屁股里  麦克沃特
This is going straight up your ass, McWatt!
该死
Oh, shit!
他撞死了基德·桑普森
He got Kid Sampson.
-他撞死了基德·桑普森  -该死
- He got Kid Sampson! - Fuck!
该死  不  天呐
Fuck! No, no! Oh, God!
不
Oh, no.
你干什么  麦克沃特
What are you doing, McWatt?
开心  开心  开心
Happy, happy, happy, happy!